<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-11T20:48:11+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Antithetical Parallels</title><subtitle>My Ramblings On Projects &amp; Other Things</subtitle><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><entry><title type="html">Future Plans</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/11/Future-Plans" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Future Plans" /><published>2018-12-11T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-12-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/11/Future-Plans</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/11/Future-Plans">&lt;p&gt;The movie trailer for Kingdom Hearts 3 just came out. Saying it with brevity, it is such a beautiful capstone to the monument of memories the series has been, to so many people. Find it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=16N6IkhxprE&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This post is kinda of an important marker-type post, so please bear with the different pacing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 4-1 semester is at an end.&lt;br /&gt;
Some of the people I know actually took the option of early graduation, for them their college life will end in just a few days.&lt;br /&gt;
Many of my friends will leave/have left the campus. They’ll undergo their last few months of college working, in short, &lt;em&gt;“at some company, at some place”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Me? Due to the perks of taking two degrees and receiving an on-campus thesis offer (and cause of a tiny problem), I potentially see myself staying here for another 2 years. 
Oh boy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that’s a lot of time.&lt;br /&gt;
To do a lot of things.&lt;br /&gt;
Or just waste in its entirety.&lt;br /&gt;
To do the former and not the latter, is what I perceive this blog can help me with.&lt;br /&gt;
Which is why I’m here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking freely, I can potentially have to construct deep differential equations, write machine learning code in Julia, for aerodynamic simulations, compete in BattleCode, play and become a pro at Artifact, work on AI problems, help create video animations, publish papers and earn money.&lt;br /&gt;
These objectives/goals are lofty.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s just that I don’t have much do otherwise now. So why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I went through some of the previous posts; agonized over the silly mistakes made (some were fixed); looked critically at the UI of the site (I dont care what you say, it’s perfect I tell ya) and hope to make a lot of posts with stellar content for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigh, this is hard.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">The movie trailer for Kingdom Hearts 3 just came out. Saying it with brevity, it is such a beautiful capstone to the monument of memories the series has been, to so many people. Find it here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Julia Context Free Grammar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/21/Julia-Context-Free-Grammar" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Julia Context Free Grammar" /><published>2018-10-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-10-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/21/Julia-Context-Free-Grammar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/21/Julia-Context-Free-Grammar">&lt;p&gt;Gists in Github Pages, lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/TestSubjector/6a407f9a4ba5996a1692c9b9f6c0eb84.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">Gists in Github Pages, lovely.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Whiskquilibrium The Game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/16/Whiskquilibrium-The-Game" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whiskquilibrium The Game" /><published>2018-10-16T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-10-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/16/Whiskquilibrium-The-Game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/10/16/Whiskquilibrium-The-Game">&lt;p&gt;On 29th and 30th September, I had the chance to participate in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://megathon.in/&quot;&gt;Megathon Hackathon at IIIT Hyderabad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Hackathons I fell are a bit of a strange thing, the novelty of cooking something up in a day or two versus the knowledge that most of what will be churned out in such events will be empty air in mere hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it’s a good thing to try out at least once and/or if you’re in a coding slump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a team consisting of me, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/legobridge&quot;&gt;Kushal Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shortstheory&quot;&gt;Arnav Dhamija&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Nischay-Pro&quot;&gt;Nischay Ram&lt;/a&gt; (appropriately called Team “CanWeGetBackToYouLater”), we devised and developed &lt;strong&gt;Whiskquilibrium&lt;/strong&gt;. A 2D platformer game in the Godot game engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the PR promoting synopsis - &lt;em&gt;It involves a cat named “Minto” trapped in a quantum world. She has the ability to shift her state between being alive and a ghostly dead form. Her presence itself changes the nature of the world around her. Can you solve the obstacles in her path that prevent her from escaping the mad world she is in?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Essentially, the game consisted of a cat character that has the power to switch colors between white and black and has to clear several levels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The blocks themselves in these levels are white, black or gray(level borders). The game mechanic is developed in the form of the cat being able to traverse through blocks of the same colour while being able to &lt;em&gt;paint&lt;/em&gt; the blocks of the opposite colour, when &lt;em&gt;you stop touching that block&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cat can jump in its default black colour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cat cannot jump when it switches to white(dead) state but has limited ability to fly which can be refilled by colouring up black blocks to white.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The number of switches possible in a level is limited.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The level can be reset at anytime (this is not a roguelike game &lt;em&gt;phew&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the sketches of the above mechanics, that we developed during the hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/8AlZv8xCgjfwt2wv5z/giphy.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; alt=&quot;Colour/ Switch&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/j9O9cCf7lmJzql78oc/giphy.gif&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; alt=&quot;Fly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The judging of the Game Dev section of the Hackathon was done by professionals from EA India (&lt;em&gt;insert jokes about DLCs here&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
Suffice to say, we did not win the 1st (given to a team that used RPG Maker to make more than 20 levels of content) or the 2nd prize (given to a team who make a game using their on OpenGL game engine, which they had been working on more than a few months, highlighting a major problem in my opinion, of hackathons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, we had a spot in the next 3 ranks (we were lazily not told the exact rank, since the &lt;strong&gt;prizes&lt;/strong&gt; for these 3 spots were the same).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Jn5q0K1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; alt=&quot;The Prize&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was actually very happy at the way the judges gave out their decisions, to be honest. They had instantly picked out people who had Ctrl C+V’ed code and assests from the net (essentially cheating). It was satisfying to watch them (those participants guilty of the aforementioned crime) being tongue-tied when the hard questions where asked. That I’ll admit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This hackathon actually helped me fulfill one my college goals, which was to make a proper effort at a developing a game. Who knows? If we are able to actually gather willpower, maybe we’ll polish this and release this on Steam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game development, in itself…is a pain. We had 4 people in our team and around 18 hours of time to understand Godot and make something. I can remember at least 5 instances, where at least one of us was on the verge of screaming, killing the other three and dancing on their corpses. The essence and the main difficulty with game development that I felt was that, everything in games are linked. It’s like how a real world behaves.&lt;br /&gt;
You want to change one move? Change everything that is dependent on that move.&lt;br /&gt;
You want to add visual indicators? Make sure that they -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;follow the camera&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;are resized properly when the camera is zoomed in/out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do not lag behing key presses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;look good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and work as they are supposed too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when you are novice (like we where), where and how to actually implement the above in a game engine(all of whom a bazillion icons to chose from) is more than a bit of a pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude,&lt;br /&gt;
the most amazing yet sad thing is, at the end of it all, we were more than happy at what we had been able to accomplish at the hackathon. We were sleep deprived of course, but seeing that the game actually came to life brought that small-persistent-warm-giddy feeling to our hearts (We had implemented sound effects. Sound effects!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I was feeling down though, was because of a conclusion I had come to. That was, while being an indie game developer will definetly be a fun and interesting career, you really need to be a bit of a masochist to be able to endure such a worklife.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">On 29th and 30th September, I had the chance to participate in the Megathon Hackathon at IIIT Hyderabad. Hackathons I fell are a bit of a strange thing, the novelty of cooking something up in a day or two versus the knowledge that most of what will be churned out in such events will be empty air in mere hours. Still, it’s a good thing to try out at least once and/or if you’re in a coding slump. With a team consisting of me, Kushal Agarwal, Arnav Dhamija and Nischay Ram (appropriately called Team “CanWeGetBackToYouLater”), we devised and developed Whiskquilibrium. A 2D platformer game in the Godot game engine. Here’s the PR promoting synopsis - It involves a cat named “Minto” trapped in a quantum world. She has the ability to shift her state between being alive and a ghostly dead form. Her presence itself changes the nature of the world around her. Can you solve the obstacles in her path that prevent her from escaping the mad world she is in? Essentially, the game consisted of a cat character that has the power to switch colors between white and black and has to clear several levels. The blocks themselves in these levels are white, black or gray(level borders). The game mechanic is developed in the form of the cat being able to traverse through blocks of the same colour while being able to paint the blocks of the opposite colour, when you stop touching that block. The cat can jump in its default black colour The cat cannot jump when it switches to white(dead) state but has limited ability to fly which can be refilled by colouring up black blocks to white. The number of switches possible in a level is limited. The level can be reset at anytime (this is not a roguelike game phew) Here are the sketches of the above mechanics, that we developed during the hackathon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting With Intro To Maching Learning Course 1- Naive Bayes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/13/Starting-With-Intro-To-Maching-Learning-Course-1-Naive-Bayes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting With Intro To Maching Learning Course 1- Naive Bayes" /><published>2018-09-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-09-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/13/Starting-With-Intro-To-Maching-Learning-Course-1--Naive%20Bayes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/13/Starting-With-Intro-To-Maching-Learning-Course-1-Naive-Bayes">&lt;p&gt;In essence, now that I’m in my 4th year, I need to think about my future. Unfortunately, as my academics can be currently be very aptly termed as a &lt;strong&gt;Disaster Zone&lt;/strong&gt;, I have to finally pick up the slack all-around. This is to make me capable of being able to bring food to my table, in the near future.&lt;br /&gt;
That, and I’m now really tired(read envious) of seeing other people achieve stuff and play games and have fun without a care in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, AI was something I wanted to get into as kid(and seeing everyone else suddenly get hyped about the same, in these last few years has been damn frustrating (The competition!)). 
Anyway, I can rant a lot about this to be sure; but let’s get on with the main topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started with the basic of the basics, the Udacity course Introduction To Machine Learning. I’ll try to put up updates about this course as I go deeper into it. 
Maybe I’ll also put up some summary notes here in the future? Let’s try with a brief one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first main topic, Naive Bayes can be (on the code side) be summed up by the following few lines -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;sklearn.naive_bayes&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GaussianNB&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clf&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GaussianNB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;features_train&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels_train&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pred&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;predict&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;features_test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;accuracy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;score&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;features_test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;labels_test&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shoutout to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://arnavdhamija.com/&quot;&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; for prodding me to &lt;em&gt;attempt&lt;/em&gt; to blog again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">In essence, now that I’m in my 4th year, I need to think about my future. Unfortunately, as my academics can be currently be very aptly termed as a Disaster Zone, I have to finally pick up the slack all-around. This is to make me capable of being able to bring food to my table, in the near future. That, and I’m now really tired(read envious) of seeing other people achieve stuff and play games and have fun without a care in the world. Now, AI was something I wanted to get into as kid(and seeing everyone else suddenly get hyped about the same, in these last few years has been damn frustrating (The competition!)). Anyway, I can rant a lot about this to be sure; but let’s get on with the main topic. I’ve started with the basic of the basics, the Udacity course Introduction To Machine Learning. I’ll try to put up updates about this course as I go deeper into it. Maybe I’ll also put up some summary notes here in the future? Let’s try with a brief one. The first main topic, Naive Bayes can be (on the code side) be summed up by the following few lines -</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BattleCode Report</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/14/BattleCode-Report" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BattleCode Report" /><published>2018-03-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/14/BattleCode-Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/03/14/BattleCode-Report">&lt;p&gt;Another very late post, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Team #369 - Markov Chain Gang, secured a position in the top 8-12th bracket of the International Qualifying bracket of BattleCode 2018.&lt;br /&gt;
We had a really good chance of getting a place in the Finals (&amp;amp; a trip to MIT!), if not for some of these reasons -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two (out of 4) of our team members got bogged down with other college related activities. So it ended with me and @legobridge
carrying the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Docker problems plagued me throughout the tournament. I lost 3-4 days cumulative in patching, updating, clearing, removing, re-installing docker to run the BattleCode scaffold.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A quota of max 4 International teams for the finals (out of the total 16 spots) was implemented for this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very honestly, it was the last point that hurt the most. The “International” teams were as a whole way more competitive; most of the top positions in the daily scrimmage rankings were captured by these teams. I understand the reason why it was done (last year had almost nil local presence) but I can’t help feel a bit salty. Mainly due to the fact that despite the other problems, we had a good chance of getting into the Finals, if not for the quota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigh, quotas are a sticky, volatile and frustrating point for many people in my country, including me, in general(&lt;em&gt;puns&lt;/em&gt;).
However, I can’t deny that the experience was lovely. Every single part of it, from regularly coding upto 20 hours at a stretch, the fun discussions on Twitch and Discord; the strategies and plans hatched and abandoned. It’s something I’ll definetly want to do again next year too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just no Docker again, please.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">Another very late post, I know.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RSS Feed &amp;amp; FeedReader Bot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/09/RSS-Feed-And-FeedReaderBot" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RSS Feed &amp; FeedReader Bot" /><published>2017-12-09T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/09/RSS-Feed-And-FeedReaderBot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/09/RSS-Feed-And-FeedReaderBot">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://testsubjector.github.io/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS Feed(s)&lt;/a&gt; is/(are?) now enabled (if they weren’t already automatically done by Github Pages).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good opportunity to talk about a bot, &lt;a href=&quot;https://storebot.me/bot/thefeedreaderbot&quot;&gt;Feed Reader Bot&lt;/a&gt;* for the popular messaging app &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.telegram.org&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this gives you is a separate chat room for all the interesting feeds you want to go through in one place. So essentially you get notifications when your favourite podcasts, news or game website or even a comic strip site has a new post.&lt;br /&gt;
And with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://instantview.telegram.org/&quot;&gt;Instant View&lt;/a&gt; feature of Telegram, you get go through a very light-weight no-nonsense view of the stuff that you want to see. A good way to keep track of the thing you want to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*The author is in no way affiliated with the Bot, except being a happy user of its free version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">RSS Feed(s) is/(are?) now enabled (if they weren’t already automatically done by Github Pages).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BattleCode 2018 Announced!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/09/BattleCode-2018-Has-Been-Announced!" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BattleCode 2018 Announced!" /><published>2017-12-09T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-12-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/09/BattleCode-2018-Has-Been-Announced!</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/12/09/BattleCode-2018-Has-Been-Announced!">&lt;p&gt;You heard it right folks, the greatest college-level AI competition will start its annual cycle in January 2018, hosted by MIT. I’ll be properly participating in it for the first time and I’m pretty hyped about it. Do have a look at their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.battlecode.org&quot;&gt;main site&lt;/a&gt;, since it will do a better job than me of explaining what BattleCode is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do participate if you can, its gonna be one heck of a ride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">You heard it right folks, the greatest college-level AI competition will start its annual cycle in January 2018, hosted by MIT. I’ll be properly participating in it for the first time and I’m pretty hyped about it. Do have a look at their main site, since it will do a better job than me of explaining what BattleCode is. Do participate if you can, its gonna be one heck of a ride.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting Up TensorFlow On Julia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/12/Setting-Up-TensorFlow-On-Julia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting Up TensorFlow On Julia" /><published>2017-11-12T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/12/Setting-Up-TensorFlow-On-Julia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/12/Setting-Up-TensorFlow-On-Julia">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt; - The instructions are chiefly for Linux (Ubuntu) users. Apologies to others. Also, beware that the steps for a GPU enabled version of TensorFlow is fraught with risks, thanks to the breakage prone shenanigans of Nvidia drivers on Ubuntu/Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, a few definitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tensorflow.org&quot;&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
TensorFlow is an open-source software library for dataflow programming across a range of tasks. It is a 
symbolic math library, and is also used for machine learning applications such as neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/malmaud/TensorFlow.jl&quot;&gt;TensorFlow,jl&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A wrapper around TensorFlow in the Julia language. Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/malmaud/TensorFlow.jl/blob/master/docs/src/why_julia.md&quot;&gt;some advantages of this&lt;/a&gt; over Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s get everything set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firstly, you need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://julialang.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;download Julia&lt;/a&gt;. For more complex ways of installation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JuliaLang/julia#source-download-and-compilation&quot;&gt;see here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt; - Download version 0.6 as it is the latest version of Julia supported for TensorFlow.jl; valid as of the date of this blog post being uploaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For CPU version of TensorFlow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now, provided you only need the &lt;em&gt;CPU version&lt;/em&gt; (don’t have or want to use an Nvidia graphic card), first access the Julia REPL. For those who downloaded the binaries, they can find the julia executable in bin folder of the downloaded files. Now, do the following in the REPL -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;julia&amp;gt; Pkg.add(&quot;TensorFlow&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;  # In the Julia REPL&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;julia&amp;gt; Pkg.build(&quot;TensorFlow&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;  # In the Julia REPL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should do it. Try typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;using TensorFlow&lt;/code&gt; in the REPL to check if the package is running perfectly. Refer to the link ahead in case you see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/malmaud/TensorFlow.jl#troubleshooting&quot;&gt;issues from the ccall or python interop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For GPU-enabled version of TensorFlow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nvidia Driver&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, that was the simple route for CPU usage. You can optimise CPU usage by &lt;a href=&quot;https://malmaud.github.io/TensorFlow.jl/latest/build_from_source.html&quot;&gt;building TensorFlow from source&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a bit outside the scope of a simple setup though.  &lt;br /&gt;
Now if you want to use the shiny Nvidia graphics card i.e use &lt;em&gt;TensorFlow with GPU enabled&lt;/em&gt;, there’s going to be a bit of pain. In the range of possible scenarios, you could faces problems ranging from lower screen resolution to a flickering screen to a complete black screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tricky thing is there’s no one-shot cure to this problem. Here’s the standard method -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo add-apt-repository ppa:graphics-drivers/ppa&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get install nvidia-current&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo reboot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be asked to enter a password to disable the secure boot after login. Be careful to not forget the password, in case of problems it can come handy.&lt;br /&gt;
If you do face problems and are not sure what to do, don’t panic. Try to access the &lt;a href=&quot;https://askubuntu.com/questions/66195/what-is-a-tty-and-how-do-i-access-a-tty&quot;&gt;TTY&lt;/a&gt; and type in the following command to get back to how things were before -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get purge nvidia-current&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo reboot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, different people with different setups + hardware + driver version will face different problems.&lt;br /&gt;
The thing that worked for me personally (after hours of successive install and purge cycles) was to install the drivers not from the command line but from the GUI of the Additional Drivers application.&lt;br /&gt;
I simply selected the version(381) I wanted (select the circle on the left), which it automatically installed. Then, Reboot -&amp;gt; disable secure boot -&amp;gt; Voila!&lt;br /&gt;
Only thing I can say is, good luck with this step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CUDA  and cuDNN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/data-center/gpu-accelerated-applications/tensorflow/&quot;&gt;this complete guide by Nvidia itself&lt;/a&gt; to download these two components. Just one thing you have to make sure is that the CUDA version you download should be 8.x and the cuDNN version should be v5.x For other versions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/malmaud/TensorFlow.jl#optional-building-the-tensorflow-library&quot;&gt;this may help&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final step&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If everything is holding together till now, then all you should need to do is -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;julia&amp;gt; Pkg.add(&quot;TensorFlow&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;  # In the Julia REPL&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;julia&amp;gt; ENV[&quot;TF_USE_GPU&quot;] = &quot;1&quot;&lt;/code&gt;  # In the Julia REPL&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;julia&amp;gt; Pkg.build(&quot;TensorFlow&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;  # In the Julia REPL&lt;br /&gt;
If typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;using TensorFlow&lt;/code&gt; and then running &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/malmaud/TensorFlow.jl#basic-usage&quot;&gt;this code&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t give an error, then congratulations! You’ve made it through the setup.&lt;br /&gt;
The actual coding now awaits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">Note - The instructions are chiefly for Linux (Ubuntu) users. Apologies to others. Also, beware that the steps for a GPU enabled version of TensorFlow is fraught with risks, thanks to the breakage prone shenanigans of Nvidia drivers on Ubuntu/Linux. First, a few definitions. What is TensorFlow? TensorFlow is an open-source software library for dataflow programming across a range of tasks. It is a symbolic math library, and is also used for machine learning applications such as neural networks. What is TensorFlow,jl? A wrapper around TensorFlow in the Julia language. Also, some advantages of this over Python. Now, let’s get everything set up. Firstly, you need to download Julia. For more complex ways of installation, see here. Note - Download version 0.6 as it is the latest version of Julia supported for TensorFlow.jl; valid as of the date of this blog post being uploaded.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oh, yes. I forgot about this blog. Also, GSoC ended.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/08/Oh,-yes.-I-forgot-about-this-blog.-Also,-GSoC-ended" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh, yes. I forgot about this blog. Also, GSoC ended." /><published>2017-11-08T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/08/Oh,-yes.-I-forgot-about-this-blog.-Also,-GSoC-ended</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/08/Oh,-yes.-I-forgot-about-this-blog.-Also,-GSoC-ended">&lt;p&gt;Whelp, this Github_page-blog-website chimera completely (or conveniently) 
slipped from my mind. However, now that I’m delving properly into the fields
of Computer Science that I’ve dreamed about as a kid (stay tuned!); this seems like the perfect place to record those experiences*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*I plan to use Medium for the things that should ideally be targeted for mass audiences. This bare-bones-but-beautiful blog isn't suited for that kind of aim. But I'll keep a record of links of all such posts here.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s make good on the above decision right now! &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@prasunk2/and-so-the-curtain-falls-on-this-gsoc-journey-69f1e4d0e4ca&quot;&gt;Here’s my post on the whole GSoC experience
(in Medium of course).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, all that has been said in this post has been said under the assumption of a sustained motivation cycle. If the chimera goes dark, you know what happened.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">Whelp, this Github_page-blog-website chimera completely (or conveniently) slipped from my mind. However, now that I’m delving properly into the fields of Computer Science that I’ve dreamed about as a kid (stay tuned!); this seems like the perfect place to record those experiences*. *I plan to use Medium for the things that should ideally be targeted for mass audiences. This bare-bones-but-beautiful blog isn't suited for that kind of aim. But I'll keep a record of links of all such posts here. Let’s make good on the above decision right now! Here’s my post on the whole GSoC experience (in Medium of course). Finally, all that has been said in this post has been said under the assumption of a sustained motivation cycle. If the chimera goes dark, you know what happened.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GSoc Tales</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/26/GSoc-Tales" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GSoc Tales" /><published>2017-06-26T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-06-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/26/GSoc-Tales</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/26/GSoc-Tales">&lt;p&gt;One month of the coding period is already up. You can read about my experiences till now at my official GSoC blog on Medium.
Links -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@prasunk2/its-fine-if-the-title-says-contributing-to-gsoc-and-open-source-improves-your-coding-skill-e6334041000f&quot;&gt;It’s fine if the title says “Contributing to GSoC and open-source improves your coding skill”, right?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@prasunk2/has-it-been-a-month-already-d5e20755dd51&quot;&gt;Has it been a month already?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>TestSubjector</name></author><summary type="html">One month of the coding period is already up. You can read about my experiences till now at my official GSoC blog on Medium. Links -</summary></entry></feed>